# **Austin Gathii**

# Software Engineer

🗣 Nairobi, Kenya 🗷 gathiiaustin@gmail.com 📞 +254 716611612 🕻 Github 🛅 LinkedIn

Personal Website

# **PROFILE**

I am a software engineer currently working as a front-end developer, specializing in React and TypeScript. My primary passion is machine learning and associated technologies which I have expressed through python-based personal projects.

I am passionate about the future of computer technology and I enjoy working in organizations where I can meaningfully contribute to that future.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Senior Frontend Developer**

Leta.ai ♂

Nairobi, Kenya

- Developed, maintained, and managed a comprehensive logistics management platform utilizing React and TypeScript.
- Integrated backend services via gRPC and implemented new features
- · Optimized performance and resolved bugs to enhance system efficiency and user experience.

**Web Developer** Sep 2022 - May 2023 Nairobi, Kenya

Standard Media Group PLC 🛮

- Maintained and debugged large API codebases built in Laravel
- Managed media websites with medium to high levels of user traffic using Laravel and Vue.js
- Rebuilt an obsolete event ticketing website in Laravel

**Data Analyst** Mar 2022 - Aug 2022 Nairobi, Kenya

Microhouse Technologies

- Managed, cleaned and maintained a large SQL database of user data in a team with 2 other engineers
- Analyzed said database to extract and derive trends and predictive data and used the matplotlib library in Python to visualize it.

**Web Developer** Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Smart Data Analytical Limited

- Developed a travel blogging site for a client based on Wordpress and created custom PHP plugins to fulfill more specific client requirements.
- Designed basic graphics and illustrations for an institution's website using Adobe Illustrator.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science, Informatics and Computer Science**

Strathmore University

2018 - 2022 Nairobi, Kenya

Earned a bachelor's degree in Computer Science over the course of 4 years that included courses on the fundamentals of computer technology as well as several specializations in the field such as mobile development, web development and database management.

gathiiaustin@gmail.com 1/2

May 2023 - present

Nairobi, Kenya

# **PROJECTS**

#### VoteTallyKE ☑ Aug 2022 – Sep 2022

- I built a computer vision system for locating and recognizing handwritten digits on scanned forms then tallying the figures with 95% accuracy.
- The input dataset was the publicly available polling station forms for the recently concluded 2022 Kenyan General Elections

#### Personal Website 🗷 May 2022 – Jul 2022

- I created fully responsive Javascript-based developer portfolio website built on the React framework with SCSS for styling.
- The website is highly customizable which also allows it to serve as a template for other developers.

### Attendance Tracking System 2

- I built a python based computer vision and machine learning system that performs facial tracking and recognition for my final year university project.
- It integrates with a camera and touchpad to provide attendance tracking of personnel within an organization or enclosed area with specific entry points

#### Green Delight 🛮 Jul 2019 - Nov 2019

- I created an android based grocery shopping application that connects buyers and sellers on a virtual marketplace
- The app also incorporates delivery riders who facilitate the physical transfer of groceries.

# SKILLS

## **Programming Languages**

Python, Typescript, Javascript, PHP

**Back End Databases** SQL, SQLite Laravel, Flask

**Front End** 

React, SCSS, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Jul 2021 - Feb 2022

2/2 gathiiaustin@gmail.com